Matthew Rockey

Columbia, MO, 65201 • 708-205-2250 • mtrkkf@umsystem.edu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Recent information technology graduate that possesses hands-on experience with software engineering, databases, and data science. Enrolled in an online master's program for data science and analytics with the goal of becoming a data scientist. Displays organizational and team collaboration skills with a desire to further grow technical abilities.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

University of Missouri - Columbia

Master of Science in Data Science and Analytics

University of Missouri - Columbia

Dean's List Recipient Honors:

Mark Twain Scholar

Graduation: May 2021 GPA: 3.91/4.00

Expected Graduation: May 2023

GPA: 4.00/4.00

Certifications: Cybersecurity Certification - 2021

SKILLS AND ABILITIES

Coding Skills:

- Python
- Java
- SQL

Database Skills:

- RDBMS/NoSQL
- ETL/Pipelines
- **Data Warehousing**
- Apache Spark

Data Science Skills:

- **Data Cleaning**
- **Data Visualization**
- Machine Learning
- Statistics/Probability

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst, Columbia, Missouri

MidwayUSA

- Performed data analysis on supply chain management, resulting in ~\$500,000 of recovered product
- Designed and deployed predictive model for future sales, reducing forecasting time and effort
- Automated quantitative scorecard measures and KPI's to identify underperforming processes
- Created and managed 300+ Power BI and SSRS reports and dashboards for internal stakeholders
- Collaborated with upper management to develop company-wide data and report standards

Database Developer Intern, Columbia, Missouri

01/2021 - 06/2021

06/2021 - Current

Odle Sales Inc.

- Developed and implemented a relational database that improved the speed of data collection and analysis
- Wrote and maintained documentation outlining the database's technical design and functionality
- Coded Python scripts to automate the ETL and data cleaning process, eliminating 80% of manual data entry

Undergraduate Research Assistant, Columbia, Missouri

09/2019 - 01/2021

University of Missouri - Columbia

- Researched and implemented innovative cloud, cybersecurity, and blockchain solutions under NSF REU grant
- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including feature testing and code reviews
- Assisted in the creation of a novel DDoS anomaly detection mechanisms using data and network analysis
- Co-authored and published 2 peer-reviewed papers pertaining to cloud and blockchain security mechanisms